Brian Dudley

3640 Old Denton Road, Apt #505 | Carrollton, TX 75007-7945 | 678-756-6863 bandrdudley@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/briandud1ey https://github.com/bandrdudley

Qualifications Summary

IT professional with over 15 years of experience in Networking and a Software Engineering. My development experience primarily focuses on multi-tier distributed application, and web design / development. Strong working knowledge in Java, JavaScript, Linux, Oracle, and various Web tools. I am a proven team player as well as an individual contributor.

Skills include:

- Advanced programming
- Certified Design Skills
- Strong collaborative skills
- Excellent problem solving
- Agile Software Development
- Project Management
- Responsive Web Design
- Object Oriented Development
- Coding and Scripting

Technical Qualifications

Languages & APIs: Java, jQuery/JavaScript, JSON, JSP, AJAX, HTML5, CSS3, REST, XML

Middleware/Databases: J2EE((EJB), JMS, Servlets), Jetty 8.1.2, Weblogic, Oracle 12g

Operating Systems: Windows 7, Linux, Unix

Packages & Tools: Eclipse, Maven, Ant, Mockito, Oracle SQL Developer 4.0

Work Experience

AT&T Services, Inc., Richardson, TX Member of the Technical Staff 2008- Current

Develop applications for the SalesExpress mobile application. Key responsibilities include:

- Developing the User Interface for the Design Solution of the Network on Demand product for 7,000 sales staff
- Programed network, history and admin screens in the mobile application utilized by 11,000 premise technicians
- Coded web-based network migration tool for the conversion of 6,000 switches in Next Generation Central offices
- Developed inventory and outage modules for a desktop application utilized by over 300 Customer Care agents nationwide.

Izmocars (Prize Corporation), Chattanooga, TN Java Developer

2006- 2008

Programmed, maintained and supported Automotive Customer Relationship Management (CRM) web application with Java Server Pages (JSP), Java, and Servlets.

- Developed and implemented two projects for Internet Lead Management (ILM) screens allowing Internet Managers to manage complete sales cycle leading to the sale of the company for 4 million dollars
- Coded web services project, parsed XML documents and maintained message queue to manage inventory and service transactions for over 400 clients nationwide.

The University of Tennessee at Chattanooga, Chattanooga, TN Student Web Developer, Research/Lab Assistant

2004- 2006

- Converted six HTML department web sites to PHP pages using CSS and templates.
- Maintained High Security Lab consisting of Windows XP, Debian Linux, BSD UNIX, Macintosh OS X clients.
- Developed a Stereoviewer and StereoFunctions applications with C++ and OpenGL.

Education and Training

Udacity, http://udacity.com/course/ud804 | Front-End Web Developer Nanodegree, Expected October 2015
University of Tennessee at Chattanooga, Chattanooga, TN | Master of Science in Computer Science, May, 2006
University of Southern Maine, Portland, ME | Bachelor of Science in Business Administration, December, 1993

Hobbies and Interests

- Parking Lot Greeter, First Baptist Church Carrollton, TX
- Meals on Wheels, VNA Dallas, TX